<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Respirework Fantasy Feed</title>
      <link>https://respirework.com/rss/empyrean-series.xml</link>
      <description>Merged fantasy content feed powered by Respirework</description>
      
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Peter David RIP (1956-2025)]]></title>
      <link>https://www.reddit.com/r/Fantasy/comments/1kvdo92/peter_david_rip_19562025/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Writer Peter David passed away last night following a long struggle with various illnesses. He was best known for his comics work (long runs on X-Factor, The Incredible Hulk, Aquaman, Young Justice, and Supergirl), his Star Trek novels, TV work such as Space Cases and Babylon 5, and a number of original novels, such as Howling Mad, Knight Life, Sir Apropos of Nothing, and more. Condolences to his wife, Kathleen O'Shea David and his family. If you can help his family out with the medical expenses, please do so. https://www.gofundme.com/f/help-peter-david
    submitted by    /u/alfredglovsnok42  
 [link]   [comments]
        <br/><a href="https://respirework.com/buy-now">Buy Onyx Storm Now – $9.99</a>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>2025-05-25T21:32:18.000Z</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Book Riot’s Deals of the Day for May 25, 2025]]></title>
      <link>https://bookriot.com/book-riots-deals-of-the-day-for-may-25-2025/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[A beautifully written Ethiopia-set family saga, occultists and the film industry in 1990s Mexico City, a visceral story set in the  wild Scottish Highlands, and more of the best book deals of the day.
        <br/><a href="https://respirework.com/buy-now">Buy Onyx Storm Now – $9.99</a>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The Book Stories We Covered This Week]]></title>
      <link>https://bookriot.com/the-book-stories-we-covered-this-week/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Here are the stories we covered ourselves this week.
        <br/><a href="https://respirework.com/buy-now">Buy Onyx Storm Now – $9.99</a>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 10:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Book Riot’s Deals of the Day for May 24, 2025]]></title>
      <link>https://bookriot.com/book-riots-deals-of-the-day-for-may-24-2025/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[The true story of the deadliest hurricane ever, a hypnotic mystery-turned-Hulu-series, vampires in 1840s Mexico, and more of the best book deals of the day
        <br/><a href="https://respirework.com/buy-now">Buy Onyx Storm Now – $9.99</a>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Prime Video Has Canceled The Wheel of Time]]></title>
      <link>https://reactormag.com/prime-video-has-canceled-the-wheel-of-time/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[The wheel weaves as Amazon Prime Video wills.
The post Prime Video Has Canceled <i>The Wheel of Time</i> appeared first on Reactor.
        <br/><a href="https://respirework.com/buy-now">Buy Onyx Storm Now – $9.99</a>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 19:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Alex Garland Will Direct A24’s Elden Ring Adaptation]]></title>
      <link>https://reactormag.com/alex-garland-will-direct-a24s-elden-ring-adaptation/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[This image is not of us studying the Elden Ring lore, but it might as well be.
The post Alex Garland Will Direct A24’s <i>Elden Ring</i> Adaptation appeared first on Reactor.
        <br/><a href="https://respirework.com/buy-now">Buy Onyx Storm Now – $9.99</a>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 15:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Reacher Star to Go On Adventure, Forget Things in Fortune]]></title>
      <link>https://reactormag.com/alan-ritchson-jerry-bruckheimer-fortune/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Memento meets Raiders of the Lost Ark, you say.
The post <i>Reacher</i> Star to Go On Adventure, Forget Things in <i>Fortune</i> appeared first on Reactor.
        <br/><a href="https://respirework.com/buy-now">Buy Onyx Storm Now – $9.99</a>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 14:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[r/Fantasy May Megathread and Book Club hub. Get your links here!]]></title>
      <link>https://www.reddit.com/r/Fantasy/comments/1kdqgen/rfantasy_may_megathread_and_book_club_hub_get/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[This is the Monthly Megathread for May. It's where the mod team links important things. It will always be stickied at the top of the subreddit. Please regularly check here for things like official movie and TV discussions, book club news, important subreddit announcements, etc.
 Last month's book club hub can be found here.
 Important Links
 New Here? Have a look at:
  
Subreddit Rules
 A guide to our many lists & resources
 Recommendation Guide
 ICYMI - r/ Fantasy originals
  
You might also be interested in our yearly BOOK BINGO reading challenge.
 Special Threads & Megathreads:
  
r/Fantasy 2025 Top Novels Results
 State of the Subreddit Discussion Post
 Pride Month
 2025 BOOK BINGO CHALLENGE
 2025 BINGO RECOMMENDATION THREAD
 Compilation of Past Bingo Squares
 2023 Top LGBTQIA+ Books List
 2024 Top Standalone Books List
 2024 Top Podcasts List
 2024 Top Self-Published Books List
  
Recurring Threads:
  
Daily Recommendation Requests and Simple Questions Thread
 Monday Show and Tell Thread
 Review Tuesday - Review what you're reading here!
 Writing Wednesday
 Friday Social
 Dealer's Room: Self-Promo Sunday
 Monthly Book Discussion
  
Book Club Hub - Book Clubs and Read-alongs
 https://preview.redd.it/6augdv1gqjye1.png?width=1920&format=png&auto=webp&s=e68eee38d1511a13163c95d6d16206ca808d26d9
 https://preview.redd.it/n9fhf8aptjye1.png?width=2000&format=png&auto=webp&s=e1e5e5a326eabd2d9699106a425657cafc2d2dbf
 Goodreads Book of the Month: Nettle & Bone by T. Kingfisher
 Run by u/fanny_bertram
  
Announcement
 Midway Discussion: May 12th: We will read until the end of Chapter 10
 Final Discussion: May 27th
 Nominations for June - May 19th
  
Feminism in Fantasy: The House of Rust by Khadija Abdalla Bajaber
 Run by u/xenizondich23, u/Nineteen_Adze, u/g_ann, u/Moonlitgrey
  
Announcement
 Midway Discussion: May 14th
 Final Discussion: May 28th
 July Read
  
New Voices: Shigidi and the Brass Head of Obalufon by Wole Talabi
 Run by u/HeLiBeB, u/cubansombrero
  
Announcement
 Monday 12 May - Midway discussion (up to the end of chapter 9)
 Monday 26 May - Final discussion
  
HEA: A Wolf Steps in Blood by Tamara Jerée
 Run by u/tiniestspoon, u/xenizondich23 , u/orangewombat
  
Announcement
 Midway Discussion
 July Read
  
Beyond Binaries: Returns in June with Small Gods of Calamity by Sam Kyung Yoo
 Run by u/xenizondich23, u/eregis
  
Announcement
  
Resident Authors Book Club: Crafting of Chess by Kit Falbo
 Run by u/barb4ry1
  
Announcement
  
Short Fiction Book Club: On summer hiatus
 Run by u/tarvolon, u/Nineteen_Adze, u/Jos_V
  
April Monthly Discussion
  
Readalong of The Thursday Next Series: First Among Sequels by Jasper Fforde
 Run by u/cubansombrero, u/OutOfEffs
  
Announcement
  
Hugo Readalong
  
Announcement & Schedule
  
Readalong of the Sun Eater Series:
  
Announcement
  
   submitted by    /u/ullsi  
 [link]   [comments]
        <br/><a href="https://respirework.com/buy-now">Buy Onyx Storm Now – $9.99</a>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>2025-05-03T11:07:21.000Z</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[OFFICIAL r/Fantasy 2025 Book Bingo Challenge!]]></title>
      <link>https://www.reddit.com/r/Fantasy/comments/1joxlrr/official_rfantasy_2025_book_bingo_challenge/</link>
      <description><![CDATA[WELCOME TO BINGO 2025!
 It's a reading challenge, a reading party, a reading marathon, and YOU are welcome to join in on our nonsense!
 r/Fantasy Book Bingo is a yearly reading challenge within our community. Its one-year mission: to explore strange new worlds, to seek out new authors and books, to boldly go where few readers have gone before. 
 The core of this challenge is encouraging readers to step out of their comfort zones, discover amazing new reads, and motivate everyone to keep up on their reading throughout the year.
 You can find all our past challenges at our official Bingo wiki page for the sub.
 RULES:
 Time Period and Prize
  
2025 Bingo Period lasts from April 1st 2025 - March 31st 2026.
 You will be able to turn in your 2025 card in the Official Turn In Post, which will be posted in mid-March 2026. Only submissions through the Google Forms link in the official post will count.
 'Reading Champion' flair will be assigned to anyone who completes the entire card by the end of the challenge. If you already have this flair, you will receive a roman numeral after 'Reading Champion' indicating the number of times you completed Bingo.
  
Repeats and Rereads
  
You can’t use the same book more than once on the card. One square = one book.
 You may not repeat an author on the card EXCEPT: you may reuse an author from the short stories square (as long as you're not using a short story collection from just one author for that square).
 Only ONE square can be a re-read. All other books must be first-time reads. The point of Bingo is to explore new grounds, so get out there and explore books you haven't read before.
  
Substitutions
  
You may substitute ONE square from the 2025 card with a square from a previous r/Fantasy bingo card if you wish to. EXCEPTIONS: You may NOT use the Free Space and you may NOT use a square that duplicates another square on this card (ex: you cannot have two 'Goodreads Book of the Month' squares). Previous squares can be found via the Bingo wiki page.
  
Upping the Difficulty
  
HARD MODE: For an added challenge, you can choose to do 'Hard Mode' which is the square with something added just to make it a little more difficult. You can do one, some, none, or all squares on 'Hard Mode' -- whatever you want, it's up to you! There are no additional prizes for completing Hard Modes, it's purely a self-driven challenge for those who want to do it.
 HERO MODE: Review EVERY book that you read for bingo. You don't have to review it here on r/Fantasy. It can be on Goodreads, Amazon, your personal blog, some other review site, wherever! Leave a review, not just ratings, even if it's just a few lines of thoughts, that counts. As with Hard Mode there is no special prize for hero mode, just the satisfaction of a job well done.
  
This is not a hard rule, but I would encourage everyone to post about what you're reading, progress, etc., in at least one of the official r/Fantasy monthly book discussion threads that happen on the 30th of each month (except February where it happens on the 28th). Let us know what you think of the books you're reading! The monthly threads are also a goldmine for finding new reading material.
 And now presenting, the Bingo 2025 Card and Squares!
 https://preview.redd.it/sm3qdnn4p8se1.png?width=1077&format=png&auto=webp&s=a6981a59a938f870a72b2999ba646329ed2fb992
 First Row Across:
  
Knights and Paladins: One of the protagonists is a paladin or knight. HARD MODE: The character has an oath or promise to keep.
 Hidden Gem: A book with under 1,000 ratings on Goodreads. New releases and ARCs from popular authors do not count. Follow the spirit of the square! HARD MODE: Published more than five years ago.
 Published in the 80s: Read a book that was first published any time between 1980 and 1989. HARD MODE: Written by an author of color.
 High Fashion: Read a book where clothing/fashion or fiber arts are important to the plot. This can be a crafty main character (such as Torn by Rowenna Miller) or a setting where fashion itself is explored (like A Mask of Mirrors by M.A. Carrick). HARD MODE: The main character makes clothes or fibers.
 Down With the System: Read a book in which a main plot revolves around disrupting a system. HARD MODE: Not a governmental system.
  
Second Row Across
  
Impossible Places: Read a book set in a location that would break a physicist. The geometry? Non-Euclidean. The volume? Bigger on the inside. The directions? Merely a suggestion. HARD MODE: At least 50% of the book takes place within the impossible place.
 
A Book in Parts: Read a book that is separated into large sections within the main text. This can include things like acts, parts, days, years, and so on but has to be more than just chapter breaks. HARD MODE: The book has 4 or more parts.
 
Gods and Pantheons: Read a book featuring divine beings. HARD MODE: There are multiple pantheons involved.
 
Last in a Series: Read the final entry in a series. HARD MODE: The series is 4 or more books long.
 
Book Club or Readalong Book: Read a book that was or is officially a group read on r/Fantasy. Every book added to our Goodreads shelf or on this Google Sheet counts for this square. You can see our past readalongs here. HARD MODE: Read and participate in an r/Fantasy book club or readalong during the Bingo year.
 
 Third Row Across
  
Parent Protagonist: Read a book where a main character has a child to care for. The child does not have to be biologically related to the character. HARD MODE: The child is also a major character in the story.
 
Epistolary: The book must prominently feature any of the following: diary or journal entries, letters, messages, newspaper clippings, transcripts, etc. HARD MODE: The book is told entirely in epistolary format.
 
Published in 2025: A book published for the first time in 2025 (no reprints or new editions). HARD MODE: It's also a debut novel--as in it's the author's first published novel.
 
Author of Color: Read a book written by a person of color. HARD MODE: Read a horror novel by an author of color.
 
Small Press or Self Published: Read a book published by a small press (not one of the Big Five publishing houses or Bloomsbury) or self-published. If a formerly self-published book has been picked up by a publisher, it only counts if you read it before it was picked up. HARD MODE: The book has under 100 ratings on Goodreads OR written by a marginalized author.
 
 Fourth Row Across
  
Biopunk: Read a book that focuses on biotechnology and/or its consequences. HARD MODE: There is no electricity-based technology.
 
Elves and/or Dwarves: Read a book that features the classical fantasy archetypes of elves and/or dwarves. They do not have to fit the classic tropes, but must be either named as elves and/or dwarves or be easily identified as such. HARD MODE: The main character is an elf or a dwarf. 
 
LGBTQIA Protagonist: Read a book where a main character is under the LGBTQIA+ umbrella. HARD MODE: The character is marginalized on at least one additional axis, such as being a person of color, disabled, a member of an ethnic/religious/cultural minority in the story, etc.
 
Five SFF Short Stories: Any short SFF story as long as there are five of them. HARD MODE: Read an entire SFF anthology or collection.
 
Stranger in a Strange Land: Read a book that deals with being a foreigner in a new culture. The character (or characters, if there are a group) must be either visiting or moving in as a minority. HARD MODE: The main character is an immigrant or refugee.
 
 Fifth Row Across
  
Recycle a Bingo Square: Use a square from a previous year (2015-2024) as long as it does not repeat one on the current card (as in, you can’t have two book club squares) HARD MODE: Not very clever of us, but do the Hard Mode for the original square! Apologies that there are no hard modes for Bingo challenges before 2018 but that still leaves you with 7 years of challenges with hard modes to choose from.
 
Cozy SFF: “Cozy” is up to your preferences for what you find comforting, but the genre typically features: relatable characters, low stakes, minimal conflict, and a happy ending. HARD MODE: The author is new to you.
 
Generic Title: Read a book that has one or more of the following words in the title: blood, bone, broken, court, dark, shadow, song, sword, or throne (plural is allowed). HARD MODE: The title contains more than one of the listed words or contains at least one word and a color, number, or animal (real or mythical).
 
Not A Book: Do something new besides reading a book! Watch a TV show, play a game, learn how to summon a demon! Okay maybe not that last one… Spend time with fantasy, science fiction, or horror in another format. Movies, video games, TTRPGs, board games, etc, all count. There is no rule about how many episodes of a show will count, or whether or not you have to finish a video game. "New" is the keyword here. We do not want you to play a new save on a game you have played before, or to watch a new episode of a show you enjoy. You can do a whole new TTRPG or a new campaign in a system you have played before, but not a new session in a game you have been playing. HARD MODE: Write and post a review to r/Fantasy. We have a Review thread every Tuesday that is a great place to post these reviews (:
 
Pirates: Read a book where characters engage in piracy. HARD MODE: Not a seafaring pirate.
 
 FAQs
 What Counts?
  
Can I read non-speculative fiction books for this challenge? Not unless the square says so specifically. As a speculative fiction sub, we expect all books to be spec fic (fantasy, sci fi, horror, etc.). If you aren't sure what counts, see the next FAQ bullet point.
 Does ‘X’ book count for ‘Y’ square? Bingo is mostly to challenge yourself and your own reading habit. If you are wondering if something counts or not for a square, ask yourself if you feel confident it should count. You don't need to overthink it. If you aren't confident, you can ask around. If no one else is confident, it's much easier to look for recommendations people are confident will count instead. If you still have questions, free to ask here or in our Daily Simple Questions threads. Either way, we'll get you your answers.
 If a self-published book is picked up by a publisher, does it still count as self-published? Sadly, no. If you read it while it was still solely self-published, then it counts. But once a publisher releases it, it no longer counts.
 Are we allowed to read books in other languages for the squares? Absolutely!
  
Does it have to be a novel specifically?
  
You can read or listen to any narrative fiction for a square so long as it is at least novella length. This includes short story collections/anthologies, web novels, graphic novels, manga, webtoons, fan fiction, audiobooks, audio dramas, and more.
 If your chosen medium is not roughly novella length, you can also read/listen to multiple entries of the same type (e.g. issues of a comic book or episodes of a podcast) to count it as novella length. Novellas are roughly equivalent to 70-100 print pages or 3-4 hours of audio.
  
Timeline
  
Do I have to start the book from 1st of April 2025 or only finish it from then? If the book you've started is less than 50% complete when April 1st hits, you can count it if you finish it after the 1st.
  
I don't like X square, why don't you get rid of it or change it?
  
This depends on what you don't like about the square. Accessibility or cultural issues? We want to fix those! The square seems difficult? Sorry, that's likely the intent of the square. Remember, Bingo is a challenge and there are always a few squares every year that are intended to push participants out of their comfort zone.
  
Help! I still have questions!
  
Don't worry, we have a Simple Questions thread every day where you can ask for clarifications.
  
Resources:
 If anyone makes any resources be sure to ping me in the thread and let me know so I can add them here, thanks!
  
2025 Bingo Recommendations List (coming soon!)
 Editable Canva Bingo Card 
 Improperly Paranoid's Simple Bingo Tracking Spreadsheet Google Drive Version and Excel Version.
 u/hellodahly made a Story Graph Challenge!
 u/shift_shaper made an interactive Bingo card!
 u/messi1045 created a Bingo Card Maker!
  
Thank You, r/Fantasy!
 A huge thank you to:
  
the community here for continuing to support this challenge. We couldn't do this without you!
 the users who take extra time to make resources for the challenge (including Bingo cards, tracking spreadsheets, etc), answered Bingo-related questions, made book recommendations, and made suggestions for Bingo squares--you guys rock!!
 the folks that run the various r/Fantasy book clubs and readalongs, you're awesome!
 the other mods who help me behind the scenes, love you all!
  
Last but not least, thanks to everyone participating! Have fun and good luck!
    submitted by    /u/happy_book_bee  
 [link]   [comments]
        <br/><a href="https://respirework.com/buy-now">Buy Onyx Storm Now – $9.99</a>]]>
      </description>
      <pubDate>2025-04-01T14:55:36.000Z</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    </channel>
  </rss>